Guide to the Gale Stokes academic papers, 1965-2012 UA 304
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Gale Stokes academic papers
1968-2010
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Stokes, Gale
UA 304
5 Linear Feet (6 cartons)
These papers contain letters, e-mails, lectures, pamphlets, notes, and administrative papers relating to the Academic career of Gale Stokes from 1965 to 2012.
Biographical Note
Gale Stokes became a History Professor at Rice University in 1968 after receiving his Ph.D. and M.A. from Indiana University. At Rice University, he has served as Dean of Humanities and Chairman of the Department of History. Professor Stokes is a three-time winner of the George R. Brown Award for Superior Teaching and won the Vucinich Prize in 1994 for the best book in his field. He has authored three books and served as president of the American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies in 2003. Professor Stokes specializes in the history of Eastern Europe, the Balkans, and Western Civilization.
Scope and Contents
These papers contain letters, e-mails, lectures, pamphlets, notes, and administrative papers relating to the Academic career of Gale Stokes from 1965 to 2012.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at woodson@rice.edu for assistance in accessing these files.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
syllabi; letters (correspondence); notes
Places
Rice University
- Series I: Graduate school papers
  - Utility of Utopia, and other papers (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vladimir Jovanovic seminar paper, University of Indiana (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chronologies (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Course Readings, Lists, Grades, and Materials, 1984-1999; 153154
  - History 101 Fall, 1992; 153164 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - History 101 Fall, 1993; 153165 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - History 101/301 Fall, 1995; 153166 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History 101/301 Fall, 1996; 153167 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - History 101/301 Fall, 1997; 153168 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History 101/301 Fall, 1999; 153169 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - History 102/302 Spring, 1990; 153170 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - History 102/302 Spring, 1993; 153171 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - History 102/302 Spring, 1994; 153172 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - History 102/302 Spring, 1996; 153173 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - History 102/302 Spring, 1997; 153174 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - History 102/302 Spring, 1999; 153175 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - History 101a: Lectures, 1970-1980; 154077 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - History 101a: Lectures, 1980-1995; 154078 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - History 102: The Essentials of European History, 1970-1980; 154079 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - History 102: The Essentials of European History, 1980-1999; 154080 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - History 102: The Essentials of European History, 1995-1999; 154081 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - History 301: Europe's Five Hundred Years, 1999; 153155 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - History 305: Russian History, 1984; 153156 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - History 305 Fall, 1982; 153176 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - History 305 Fall, 1984; 153177 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - History 305 Fall, 1986; 153178 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - History 305 Fall, 1996; 153179 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - History 305 Spring, 2004; 153180 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - History 305 lecture notes, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - History 345: First Half of First Semester, 153229 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - History 345: Second Half of First Semester, 154072 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - History 345 Syllabus, Maps, Class List, Etc., 1968; 153181 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - History 345 Admin Details, 1970; 153182 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - History 345 Administration Fall, 1974; 153183 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - History 345 Early Modern Russia Fall, 1975; 153184 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - History 345 Fall, 1972; 153185 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - History 345 Fall, 1977; 153186 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - History 345, 1979; 153187 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - History 346, 1969; 153188 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - History 346, 1971; 153189 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - History 346 Admin, 1973; 153190 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - History 346 Spring, 1974; 153191 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - History 346 Russian Revolution Spring, 1975; 153192 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - History 346 Fall, 1976; 153193 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - History 346 Russian Revolution Fall, 1978; 153194 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - History 346, 1980; 153195 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - History 346: First Half of Semester, 1987; 154073 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - History 346: Second Half of Semester, 1986; 154074 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - History 346: Russian Revolution Role Playing, 154075 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Balkan History, 1970-1990; 154092 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Balkan History Fall, 1975; 153196 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - History 389: Eastern Europe Lectures, 1998; 154076 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - History 390 Spring, 1993; 153197 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - History 390 Spring, 1994; 153198 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - History 390 Fall, 1995; 153199 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Balkan History Fall, 1981; 153202 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - History 389 Fall, 1992; 153203 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - History 389 Fall, 1993; 153204 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Balkan History Admin, 1971-1975; 153205 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - History 397: The Orthodox Church, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - History 453 Fall, 1973; 153200 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - History 453 Balkan, 1978; 153206 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - History 453 Spring, 1984; 153207 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - History 458, 1975; 153208 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - History 478 Spring, 1987; 153209 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - History 490 Symonds, 1996-1997; 153211 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - History 494 Eastern Europe Since 1945 Spring, 1990; 153210 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - History 493 Fall, 1974; 153212 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - History 493, n.d.; 153213 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - History 494 East Europe Spring, 1988; 153214 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - History 494: Eastern Europe After WWI, 1988; 153157 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - History 494 Fall, 1988; 153215 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Nationalism Seminar Spring, 1995; 153216 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - History 533 Fall, 1987; 153217 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - History 533 Fall, 1989; 153218 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - History 590 Fall, 1998; 153219 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - History 590 Spring, 2004; 153220 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Master of Liberal Studies (MLS) 603, 2007; 153163 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Slides, 1994; 153225 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Transparencies, 1993; 153226 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Maps and Charts, 1997; 153227 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Series III: Lectures and talks, ca. 1965-2010; 153228
  - Szporluk Articles and Notes, 1987-1988; 154093 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "The End of History?" (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "Is it possible to be optimistic about Eastern Europe?" (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Galveston Talk, 1990; 153224 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Nationalism topics ("Cognition, Consciousness, and Nationalism," "The Costs of Nationhood: The Patentarina in Serbia 1879," "Introduction of Nationalism into Serbian Politics," and more), 1988-1994 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "Nineteenth Century Serbia: So What?" (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "A Past for the Future," 1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Serbian topics (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Thinking About 1989, 2009-2010 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - New Ideas in Eastern Europe, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - University of Illinois Yugoslav Workshop, 1985; 153159 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Woman's Institute - Spring, 1973; 154094 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Woman's Institute Talks, 2006; 153222 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Woman's Institute, 2006; 153221 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Lectures and talks named by the host event (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Lectures and talks - notes and fragments (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Series IV: Books, book reviews, articles, 1970-2012
  - Articles by Stokes (published in News Net, Lingua Franca, Problems and Post-Communism), 1999-2009 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Articles by Stokes (published in Washington Post, Newsday), 1991-2005 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Articles by Stokes (Box 4, Folder 3-5)
  - Essays related to Stokes' books (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Harcourt Royalties, 1996-2001; 153162 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Book reviews written by Stokes, 1970-2012 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Articles written by others (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Ephemera (programs and notes) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Serbian history notebooks (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Series V: Correspondence, 1971-1998; 154095
  - Correspondence, 1971-1972; 154112 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1973; 154113 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1974; 154114 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1976; 154115 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1975; 154116 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1977; 154117 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1978; 154118 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1979; 154119 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1980; 154120 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, ca. 1980 - letter to Stokes from Videk Pecak, friend in Slovenia from when Stokes stayed with Pecak's family with a group "Experiment in International Living" (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1981; 154121 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1982; 154122 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1984; 154123 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1985; 154124 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1986; 154125 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1987; 154126 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1988; 154127 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1989; 154128 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1990; 154104 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1992; 154102 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1993; 154101 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1994; 154100 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995; 154099 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1996; 154098 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1997; 154097 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1998; 154096 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center Correspondence, 1990-1991; 154103 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Series VI: Grants, Recommendations, and Activities, 1968-2006; 154105
  - Recommendations, 1980-1990; 154106 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Recommendations, 1971-1980; 154107 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Football, 1985-1989; 154108 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Dean's Files - Personal, 2002; 154109 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Office of Continuing Studies (OCS), 1998; 153223 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Center for the Study of Languages (CSL), 2002-2005; 154110 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Salary, Grants, Leave, Activities, Promotion, 1968-2006; 154111 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Omladina Skupstinas (Box 6, Folder 18)